export const SCULPTUREA2022 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The main reason for studying textiles is to enable students to",
A: "produce and care for fabrics.",
B: "produce their own uniforms.",
C: "sell textile products.",
D: "set up more textiles factories.",
answer: "D. weaving.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Ashantis and Anlos are noted for",
A: "adinkra production.",
B: "batik work.",
C: "discharge printing.",
D: "kente weaving.",
answer: "C. shedding, picking and beat up.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. Yarns are packaged in",
A: "cones and spools",
B: "cheese and cones.",
C: "cones and skiener.",
D: "skiener and cheese.",
answer: "D. introduce twist fibres.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. The percentage of moisture in cotton fibre is",
A: "1%.",
B: "4%.",
C: "8%.",
D: "12%.",
answer: "D. obtain the required structure.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Select from the list, the strongest natural fibre.",
A: "Cotton",
B: "Flax",
C: "Silk",
D: "Wool",
answer: "D. Whorl.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. When cotton fabrics are wet, they become",
A: "light.",
B: "lustrous.",
C: "strong.",
D: "weak.",
answer: "D. patchy effect.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Select the correct order of fibre preparations from the options.",
A: "Retting, scutching, spinning",
B: "Retting, spinning, scutching",
C: "Scutching, retting, spinning",
D: "Spinning, retting, scutching",
answer: "C. embroidery.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. The major difference between woollen and worsted yarns is that",
A: "woollen yarns are coarser.",
B: "woollen yarns are weaker.",
C: "worsted yarns are expensive.",
D: "worsted yarns are hard-twisted.",
answer: "B. rayon.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Identify the fibre that is obtained from Bombyx mori.",
A: "Coir",
B: "Silk",
C: "Sisal",
D: "Wool",
answer: "A. cotton fibre.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Wax and oil in cotton are removed by",
A: "chemical processing.",
B: "manual processing.",
C: "mechanical means.",
D: "physical means.",
answer: "A. chemical processing.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Satin fabrics consist almost entirely of",
A: "pile loops.",
B: "ply yarns.",
C: "warp floats.",
D: "weft floats.",
answer: "D. weft floats.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. Floating occurs in weaving when",
A: "warp yarns break and are not mended.",
B: "warp yarns are entangled in fabric.",
C: "weft yarns move over one warp yarns.",
D: "weft yarns move over two or more ends.",
answer: "D. weft yarns move over two or more ends.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Which of the following order of interlacing results in a twill weave?",
A: "1/8",
B: "1/7",
C: "1/5",
D: "1/3",
answer: "D. 1/3",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Which of the following describes tapestry?",
A: "Hand-woven decorative fabric with large number of wefts.",
B: "Hand-woven fabric on warp yarns.",
C: "Machine-woven decorative fabric with large threads.",
D: "Machine-woven fabric on warp yarns.",
answer: "A. Hand-woven decorative fabric with large number of wefts.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. Warping is to beam as weaving is to",
A: "pulley.",
B: "raddle.",
C: "shuttle.",
D: "spindle.",
answer: "C. shuttle.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. In weaving, the method of arranging ends on the shafts is",
A: "heddling.",
B: "raddling.",
C: "reeding.",
D: "warping.",
answer: "A. heddling.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Select the best description of a twill fabric.",
A: "Diagonal lines are pronounced.",
B: "It is similar to check fabric.",
C: "The fabric is harsh.",
D: "The surface is fluffy.",
answer: "A. Diagonal lines are pronounced.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. During beaming, the raddle is used to",
A: "assist the reed.",
B: "make heddling easier.",
C: "roll the warp.",
D: "spread the warp ends.",
answer: "D. spread the warp ends.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Weaves are first designed on the point paper to",
A: "make the fabric last long.",
B: "make the loom ready for weaving.",
C: "obtain the required fabric.",
D: "obtain the required structure.",
answer: "D. obtain the required structure.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Which of the options help in identifying twill weaves?",
A: "compactness of weave",
B: "Diagonal lines",
C: "Looping surface",
D: "Lustrous appearance",
answer: "B. Diagonal lines",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. The process of fabric construction in which loops are produced is",
A: "applique.",
B: "crocheting.",
C: "embroidery.",
D: "tapestry.",
answer: "B. crocheting.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. In screen preparation, the coated screen is dried in the",
A: "dark room.",
B: "open shade.",
C: "Lon oven.",
D: "sun.",
answer: "B. open shade.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. During dyeing, it is important to keep the fabric submerged in the dye solution to avoid",
A: "bleeding.",
B: "fading.",
C: "patchy effect.",
D: "over saturation.",
answer: "C. patchy effect.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. The folding and marbling techniques of resist can be achieved in",
A: "batik.",
B: "printing.",
C: "tie-dye.",
D: "tritik.",
answer: "C. tie-dye.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. One of the reasons for textile decoration is to",
A: "attract potential customers.",
B: "make the cloth resistant to bleaching.",
C: "make the fabric durable.",
D: "improve washability.",
answer: "A. attract potential customers.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Select the correct order of extracting vegetable dyes.",
A: "Add water, boil, strain and grind",
B: "Boil, strain, grind and add water",
C: "Grind, add water, boil and strain",
D: "Strain, grind, add water and boil",
answer: "C. Grind, add water, boil and strain",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. A tie-dye technique that requires stitching is",
A: "knotting.",
B: "marbling.",
C: "splashing.",
D: "tritiking.",
answer: "A. knotting.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Select the most appropriate tool used to create designs in resist dyeing.",
A: "Brayer",
B: "Diffuser",
C: "Squeegee",
D: "Tjanting",
answer: "D. Tjanting",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. In screen printing, good registration marks are needed to help each colour to",
A: "blend the background.",
B: "fall outside the motif.",
C: "fit in the planned position.",
D: "overlap with the motif.",
answer: "C. fit in the planned position.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. The liberalization of imported textile products is the cause of",
A: "decline of local textiles industries.",
B: "development of local industries.",
C: "high patronage of local fabrics.",
D: "increase in prices of local fabrics.",
answer: "A. decline of local textiles industries.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Select from the options the meaning of the Adinkra symbol in Figure 1.",
A: "Faithfulness and endurance",
B: "Hope and peace",
C: "Patience and tolerance",
D: "Strength and laughter",
answer: "A. Faithfulness and endurance",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. A motif repeated in a negative and positive pattern results in",
A: "a counter change design.",
B: "a full drop design.",
C: "an all over design.",
D: "an ogee design.",
answer: "A. a counter change design.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Indantrine is a type of dye classified under",
A: "acid.",
B: "azoic.",
C: "reactive.",
D: "vat.",
answer: "D. vat.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Finishes are purposely designed to",
A: "bleach colouring matter in a fabric.",
B: "increase the lustre of a fabric.",
C: "mercerize calico after bleaching.",
D: "get rid of impurities in gray baft.",
answer: "B. increase the lustre of a fabric.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Identify the statement that explains the reason for scouring fabrics.",
A: "Adds more dye to the fabric",
B: "Adds value to the fabric",
C: "To make product durable",
D: "To remove impurities",
answer: "D. To remove impurities",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Identify the tool in Figure 2.",
A: "Diffuser",
B: "Roller",
C: "Squeegee",
D: "Tjanting",
answer: "C. Squeegee",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. The tool in Figure 2 is used for",
A: "cleaning the printing table.",
B: "marking fabric before printing.",
C: "straightening fabric on the table.",
D: "spreading ink for printing.",
answer: "D. spreading ink for printing.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. The process applied to cotton fabrics to prevent shrinkage is termed",
A: "calendering.",
B: "mercerization.",
C: "sanforization.",
D: "tentering.",
answer: "C. sanforization.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Choose the appropriate duty of a textile designer.",
A: "Cutting of patterns for dresses",
B: "Establishing textiles industries",
C: "Mixing dyes for printing",
D: "Organizing motifs on paper",
answer: "D. Organizing motifs on paper",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Creating an image based on a plan is",
A: "designing.",
B: "drawing.",
C: "knitting.",
D: "stitching.",
answer: "A. designing.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},


]